Don't rush to take action first.
你们先别急着动手
If he was originally here to kill,
如果他一开始就是为了杀人
someone should have already died by now.
那么现在应该已经有人丧命了
Does that mean we can relax?
也就是说 我们可以放心了吧
That's hard to say.
这可难说
Trying to understand the thoughts of Lemmings is futile.
要是你想揣摩旅鼠军团的想法的话 那是没有用的
Mr. Iwa.
岩先生
Anyway, this guy is a wanted criminal.
不管怎么说 这家伙都是通缉犯
Defeat him and arrest him.
我们先击溃他 再将他逮捕吧
Don't forget that this is all happening in front of everyone.
你别忘了 我们现在可是在众目睽睽之下
Polka, Polka.
波尔卡波尔卡
He's probably even scarier than that cop.
他大概是比那名警察 还要可怕很多的人
I can tell.
这我看得出来
Is that the soul of the person "that guy" killed?
那些是 被“那家伙”杀掉的人的灵魂吗
Hatred and fear are struggling inside?
仇恨和恐惧正在互相抗衡着
Your arm strength is pretty good.
你的臂力不错啊
I don't know how your abdominal muscles are trained, though.
不知道你的腹肌锻炼得怎么样
I did remind you that we're in front of everyone.
我刚才应该提醒过你 这是在众目睽睽之下了吧
This guy really underestimated me.
我还真是被这家伙给小瞧了呢
Are you looking for me?
原来你要找的人是我呀
Huh? Is this a new way of hitting on someone?
咦 这是一种新的搭讪方式吗
Misaki!
美咲
No, I can't use magic in front of the police.
不行 我不能当着警察的面使用魔法
If anything goes wrong,
稍有差池
my peaceful life will be gone forever.
安稳的生活便将永远离我而去
I couldn't live peacefully if I became "that guy's" enemy.
再者说 如果和“那家伙”为敌 我根本不可能得到安稳的生活
Arase!
荒濑
He and Shagrua are similar, even though they have different traits.
虽然倾向不同 但他和夏古鲁亚是同一类型的人
He was born as a human but exists beyond normal logic.
他们都是生为人身 却是超脱常理一般的存在
The only choice in front of me is
那么 摆在我面前的只有一种选择
to abandon her and run away.
那就是舍弃她 然后独自逃走
Polka.
波尔卡
Maybe it's because I failed to reincarnate.
也许是因为我转生失败了吧
Master, it seems that
师父 看来我
I have become an irreparable idiot.
变成了一个无可救药的笨蛋啊
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《尸体如山的死亡游戏》
(Episode 5: The Monster)
(第5集 The Monster -怪物-)
What is that?
那是什么
Polka?
波尔卡
Although I can't see anything, you must be Polka, right?
虽然我什么都看不见 但你是波尔卡 对吧
Be quiet. Hurry up and run away now.
你给我安静点 趁现在赶快逃走
What was that sound just now?
刚才那是什么声音
Can you see everything in the dark?
你在黑暗中也能看清一切吗
Misaki!
美咲
That's not something that can be said casually.
那可不是随随便便就能往外说的事情
I know someone will get angry if I say it,
要是我说出来的话 会有人生气的
so let's end the conversation here.
所以我们的沟通到此结束
It's a pity.
真是遗憾
Wait, don't act too hastily.
等等 你先别急着动手
He is an honest child and has nothing to do with this matter.
他是个老实的孩子 跟这件事可没关系哦
So, now that I've told you everything,
怎么样 我都告诉你了哦
are you satisfied?
你满意了吗
If you're still not satisfied, let me offer you some benefits.
如果你还是不满意的话 那我再给你提供点福利吧
She wants to use the paralyzing effect of saliva.
她是要利用唾液的麻痹作用
I can't even bite through this bandage.
我根本咬不穿这层绷带啊
I was just kidding around.
我开玩笑的啦
We indirectly kissed,
我们可是间接接吻了哦
you should be happy about it.
你应该觉得很高兴吧
Only relying on the saliva left on a licked fork,
仅凭舔过的叉子上的那些唾液
it's impossible to fully achieve the numbing effect.
是没法完全达到麻痹效果的
But thank you anyway.
但是 多谢你了
Thanks to you, I finally calmed down and set up the magic.
多亏了你 我终于冷静下来 把魔法给设置好了
This scene is really miserable.
我们还真是惨败呢
I thought I could easily defeat him, but I couldn't even lift a finger.
我本以为可以轻松解决他 到头来却发现我连手都插不上
Let's bring all our equipment next time.
下次我们还是全副武装再过来吧
You guys are talking so lightly.
你们说得还真是轻松啊
Sorry, since encountering that kind of monster,
抱歉 既然我都见识到那种怪物了
my courage is not big enough to try to fight it barehanded.
我的胆子可没有大到 能试图以赤手空拳对付那种家伙
The place where you are sitting is a non-smoking area.
你坐的地方是禁烟席
You're back, Lemmings
你回来了啊 旅鼠军团
You've been gone for a long time.
你去了好久啊
It's not common for you.
就你而言这可并不多见
What?
你说什么
Is it?
是吗
Jimba has already been killed.
原来阵场已经被杀了啊
Whoever did it doesn't matter anymore.
算了 反正那本来就是一件 让谁来收拾都可以的案子
I look forward to your performance in the future.
往后我也很期待你的表现
Nezu.
根津
Anything else?
你还有什么事吗
Really?
真的吗
That guy is like an urban legend similar to Shinjuku.
那家伙可是类似 新宿的都市传说一般的存在啊
They always appear silently
他们总是悄声无息地出现
and complete their work
然后默默地完成工作
as if they are everywhere,
好似无处不在
so they are called the Lemmings
所以他们被称作“旅鼠军团”
Fortunately, you guys are safe.
幸好你们平安无事
Yeah, we are really lucked out.
就是说啊 我们真是赚到了
However,
但是
Polka should've used up a lot of magic this time.
波尔卡你这次用掉了很多魔力吧
I replenished a lot of magic from
不过我从围绕在那名绷带男人 身边的怨灵身上
the grudges around the bandaged man.
补充了很多魔力
Thank you.
谢谢你
Why are you thanking me?
你为什么要跟我道谢
You helped me.
因为你帮了我
Did you tell him
你将不能说的事
what can't be said?
告诉他了吧
No problem.
你不用这么客气
You also saved me.
毕竟你也救了我
It's mutual.
所以我们就扯平啦
If you feel like helping someone, whether you just met them
不论是前一秒认识的人 还是认识了五年的人
or have known them for five years, do so.
如果心里冒出想要帮助那个人的念头 那你尽管去帮就是了
Boy,
少年
perhaps you will live through a considerably long life where no matter
恐怕你将度过一段相当漫长的人生
if it is one second or a hundred years, it will not make much difference for you.
一秒还是一百年 对你而言并无多少差别
Therefore,
所以
measuring things with the length of time has no meaning.
你用时间的长短来衡量事物 是毫无意义的
The longer your life is lived,
你度过的人生愈是长久
the more emotions will accumulate within you
那积攒得愈发厚重的情感
and at critical moments
就会在紧要关头
they will make your body take action unconsciously.
让你的身体下意识地采取行动
With this fragile body of mine,
光靠现在这副脆弱的身躯
I am unable to protect anyone,
我不仅无法保护任何人
let alone take care of myself.
甚至也自身难保
Misaki.
美咲
Takumi.
匠
And the real Polka.
还有真正的波尔卡
I know nothing about this world
我对这个世界一无所知
and there are many things I want to ask you,
我还有很多事想请教你们
including your own affairs.
包括你们的事在内
What's wrong? Why so serious?
你怎么了 为什么这么一本正经的啊
I have thoroughly understood that
我已经彻底明白了
no matter how short the time we spend together,
无论相处的时间多么短暂
I don't need to sacrifice the people who once laughed with me
需要舍弃曾一起欢笑的人 才能换来的安稳生活
in exchange for a peaceful life.
我才不需要
I didn't expect him to still be alive.
没想到你还活着啊
You completely fooled me.
我真是彻头彻尾地被你给骗了啊
Polka.
波尔卡
Game over.
游戏时间到此结束
So
所以
I want to work.
我要准备开始工作了
Work?
工作
After yesterday's incident, I finally figured it out.
经过昨天的那件事 我算是想明白了
My magic power is not enough yet.
我现在魔力还不够
If I want to have a stable life in this world,
若是我想要在这边的世界 获得安稳的生活
money is essential.
金钱果然还是必不可少的
I deeply understand this.
你的结论还真是现实啊
Are you going to come out with that large skeleton again?
你又要搬出那具大型骸骨了吗
It will attract the Mobile Investigation Team.
那可是会引来机动队的啊
Spirit of Dead Thread can be used for combat,
虽说死灵术可以用于战斗
but it has many other uses.
但它还有许多其他的用法
For example,
比如说
signing a contract with a self-aware soul
和保有自我的灵魂签订契约
and allowing it to possess something to make it move.
让它附身在某样东西上 再让它动起来
That's my mechanical pencil.
那是我的自动铅笔
It fell to the ground, let me borrow it for a moment.
它掉在地上了 稍微借我用一下
Sure.
可以哦
The underground of this building
这栋大楼的地下
has rational souls.
有着保有理智的灵魂
I made a contract with it and tried to possess the mechanical pencil.
我跟它签订了契约 并试着让它附身到了自动铅笔上
YOU AND CLARISSA, WHO WORKS AS AN INTERMEDIARY, HAVE A CLOSE RELATIONSHIP. IT IS MY GREAT HONOR TO MEET YOU ALL.
(能与那个从事中介的克拉丽莎的 诸位知己结识 在下倍感荣幸)
Its writing is unexpectedly good.
它的文笔居然这么好
I AM HOSOROGI, WHO DIED HERE FIVE YEARS AGO.
(我是五年前在此殒命的细吕木)
Amazing!
好厉害
But the things written down are quite shocking.
可它写下来的东西也太劲爆了吧
Only I can engage in this kind of business that uses magic to make a living.
要是我像这样 将只有我能用的魔法拿来做生意的话
Perhaps I can monopolize this market.
也许我可以垄断这方面的市场
Actually, I have even prepared the shop sign.
其实我连招牌都做好了
ANY COMMISSION - THE SHOP IS AWESOME
(啥都能接 THE店 魔法OK 好棒哦)
How is it?
你觉得如何
I can help out too.
我也帮忙做招牌了哦
Do you want to live a peaceful life?
你是想过上安稳的生活吧
I am well aware that your true identity is a terrifying monster.
我很清楚你的真实身份 是一个可怕的怪物
As someone like me, a small character, you could easily kill me.
像我这种小角色 你轻而易举地就能杀掉
But I still have to say it.
但我还是要跟你说
Is there something wrong with your head?
你的脑子有毛病吧
I HAVE AN IDEA TO EARN MONEY
(想赚钱的话 我有个好主意)
I saw that
我看到了
your profession is
您的职业
related to medical care.
跟医疗有关 对吧
You are right.
你说得没错
I can feel that there is a blockage of air in your right leg.
我能感觉到您的右腿当中有气阻塞住
You're correct.
你 你说的没错
My right leg was fractured recently and I am currently undergoing rehabilitation.
我前阵子右腿骨折了 最近正在复健
Why did it start moving?
它怎么动起来了
Playing games should be done in moderation.
玩游戏要适度
Did you even know about this kind of thing?
连这种事你都能知道吗
It's amazing that you can actually make money from this.
居然真的能凭这个赚钱
Very impressive, right?
我们很厉害吧
It's hard to imagine.
真是难以想象
The mechanical pencil itself even drew the sign.
就连那块招牌 都是自动铅笔它自己画出来的
You earned 100 000 Yen in just one week.
一周就赚了十万啊
However, divination?
不过对于占卜来说
If you want divination to look like the real deal,
若要让占卜看上去像那么回事
you need to master cold reading and hot reading techniques.
就需要掌握冷读术和热读术
In fact, you have done it quite convincingly.
你们实际上做得还蛮有模有样的嘛
Based on the name and date of birth written by the client at reception,
我会根据客人在接待处 写下的姓名和出生年月日
I gather information and
来收集情报
share it by using this eye as a tool.
并借助这颗眼球和你们共享资料
Then we rely on the power of Polka.
接着再发挥波尔卡的力量
I died last month because of overeating.
我上个月因为暴饮暴食而死掉了
You lost someone important to you last month.
您上个月失去了对您很重要的人
How do you know about this?
为什么你会知道这件事
The key to opening the door to a new life
能够为您打开崭新生活之门的钥匙
must be engraved on the tombstone in the courtyard.
想必就刻在庭院里的墓碑上
Tombstone?
墓碑
The tombstone of Little Mi, our cat who died last year?
你说的是我去年死掉的宠物 小咪的墓碑吗
Could it be
你说的该不会是
the password for the safe?
保险箱的密码吧
We together created you, a skilled diviner who never misses a shot.
是我们一同造就了 你这名弹无虚发的占卜师
But no matter what,
可是啊
in the eyes of others, your mechanical pencil is just a trick to deceive them.
你那支自动铅笔再怎么说 在他人眼中就是拿来障眼的魔术吧
IT'S BEST IF THEY HAVE SUCH THOUGHTS. AT FIRST, THEY CAME OUT OF SUSPICION TO INVESTIGATE.
(人们能产生那种想法真是再好不过了 他们起初会因怀疑而前来一探究竟)
THEN THEY WILL ALL BECOME PAWNS LAID DOWN FOR MORE EFFECTIVE BRAINWASHING.
(随后都将变成 为了更有效的洗脑而布下的棋子)
You called it brainwashing?
你说这样是洗脑吗
After all, Polka's wish is to have a stable life.
毕竟波尔卡的愿望是 得到“安稳的生活”嘛
These are the first earnings I've made in this world.
这些是我在这个世界赚到的第一笔钱
Let's split it equally among five people.
我们五个人平分吧
Five people?
五个人
Me, Misaki
我和美咲
Takumi, real Polka and Mr. Hosorogi.
匠和真正的波尔卡 以及细吕木先生
You are really someone who follows the rules.
你这人可真是讲规矩
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
Just consider this money as a thank-you gift for borrowing this body.
你就把这笔钱当作是我 借用这具身体的谢礼就行了
Is it trying to express that it doesn't want to accept this money?
它是想表达自己不想收下这笔钱吗
Hmm, it says that it hasn't been able to help with anything.
嗯 它说自己什么忙都没帮上
That's true. Money shouldn't be a surprise to the real Polka.
也是 真正的波尔卡 应该对金钱见怪不怪了吧
I remember you once saying you couldn't retrieve all of your memories.
我记得你曾经说过 自己没能获得全部的记忆吧
Actually, the home of Polka Shinoyama is…
其实四乃山波尔卡的家是…
Hey, hey, what's going on?
喂喂 这是什么情况
Oh my, did we disturb everyone?
哎呀 我们是否惊扰到各位了
Greetings to everyone.
诸位贵安
We found it, we found it!
找到你了找到你了
Polka is actually here.
波尔卡 你人居然真的在这里
It's been half a month since we last met, right, Uncle Polka?
我们半个月没有照面了吧 波尔卡叔叔
Hmm, could it be…
咦 难道…
They are Kazuki Shinoyama and Shizuki Shinoyama,
他们是四乃山华月和四乃山紫月
the twin siblings.
是一对双胞胎姐弟
And they are also the nephew and niece of this body.
他们还是这具身体的侄子和侄女
The situation is not good. I have to figure out a way to bluff my way through.
情况不妙 我得想办法糊弄过去
Did you guys mistake me for someone else?
你们认错人了吧
I am the Corpse God
吾乃“尸神殿”
from a distant land. A wizard who mistakenly arrived here.
来自遥远的彼岸 是一个误入此地的魔法师
What is that for?
你那是什么角色扮演啊
And what does the name "Corpse God" mean anyway?
再说尸神殿这名字又是什么意思
Corpse God, a temple for corpses?
尸神 尸体的神殿
It sounds pretty cool, though.
听起来还蛮酷的嘛
Is that so?
这名字哪里酷了
Don't worry, Shizuki.
你别急 紫月
He was probably influenced by those two commoners.
他恐怕是受到了 那两个庶民的指使吧
If it weren't for that,
若不是这样
Uncle Polka wouldn't escape from home.
波尔卡叔叔也不可能从家里逃了出去
It's really bad.
这下糟了
If they noticed I'm not Polka,
要是被发现我不是波尔卡本人的话
a peaceful life would be far away from me.
安稳的生活将会离我远去
Never mind, let's put this matter aside for now.
罢了 这件事暂且放到一边
We came here today as guests.
我们今天是作为顾客过来的
Can you show us
可以让我们见识一下
your expertise in divination?
你拿手的占卜吗
That's a silly question.
真是愚蠢的问题
Everything depends on opportunity.
凡事讲究一个机缘
Please come back next time.
请你们下次再来吧
We will be open from 10am tomorrow.
我们明天是从早上十点开始营业哦
Young lady,
这位大小姐
can you please go back first today?
今天可以请你们先回去吗
Oh my, how strange.
哎呀 真是奇怪
I don't remember allowing you to interrupt me.
我不记得自己曾允许过你插嘴
A commoner dares to give me his opinion.
不过是区区一个庶民 居然还敢对我提意见
If I say no, what are you going to do about it?
如果我说不愿意 你打算怎么做
I will call the police.
我姑且会先报告给警方
According to common sense, I should do so.
按常理来讲 我本就应该这么做啊
You led a group of people to aggressively break into the closed store.
你领着一帮人气势汹汹地 闯入已经关门的店铺
As a frightened ordinary citizen,
我这备受惊吓的小百姓
my only choice is to call the police.
也只能选择报警了吧
What?
什么
You're really joking.
你可真会说笑
Do you know who we are?
你知道我们是谁吗
A person who belittles someone they just met without hesitation
你二话不说便将初次见面的人 贬得一文不值
is nothing but a vulgar nouveau riche.
你们不就是下流的暴发户吗
I am…
我可是…
Please calm down, young lady.
请您冷静下来 大小姐
This guy might be recording
这家伙恐怕正在录音
or even broadcasting live on site.
他也有可能正在现场直播
It's not wise to reveal our identities here.
我认为我们在这里搬出名号绝非上策
What's wrong?
怎么了
Are you asking those guys in black
你嘴上吵不过
to beat me up
就转而拜托那些穿黑衣服的兄弟
because you can't win an argument with me?
对我动手吗
You're going too far.
你这家伙不要太过分了
It's enough now, thank you.
已经可以了 谢谢你
I know
我知道
you intentionally drew attention to yourself for me.
你是为了我 才会故意将对方的矛头 转移到自己的身上
This girl
这女孩
is about to cry.
已经快要哭出来了
Wh-What nonsense are you talking about?
你 你在说什么蠢话
Hey Polka, what are you doing…
喂波尔卡 你在做…
Did you just ask me to do a divination for you?
你刚才说 想让我替你们占卜一下 对吧
Don't worry.
别担心
You have a future.
你们拥有未来
Rest assured, I will protect you.
放心吧 我会保护你们
Wh-What are you talking about?
你 你在说什么啊
You're just Polka.
你不过只是波尔卡而已
You've got the wrong person,
你们认错人了
but I know Polka.
但我认识波尔卡
He said,
他是这样说的
"I will go home tomorrow,
“我明天会回家”
so you guys can go back today."
所以你们今天先回去吧
Okay, I got it.
嗯 我知道了
Don't worry about it.
你就放心吧
Can someone save these two children?
谁来救救这两个孩子
I will protect them.
我会保护他们的
Calling it an evil spirit is not quite accurate.
说它是恶灵的话不太准确
I can feel that it wants to protect those two people,
我能够感觉到它是想要保护那两个人
but its mind is a bit unclear now.
但它已经有点神智不清了
Do you believe what it says?
你要相信它说的话吗
I cannot just sit and watch.
我没法坐视不管
You are really kind-hearted.
你这人还真是善良啊
Hmm, yes, a little.
嗯 我的确是有一点
They made me recall those children who loved to act tough.
因为他们让我想起了 那些爱逞强的孩子们
I see.
原来是这样啊
Hey, hey.
喂喂
Are you really going back to Polka's house tomorrow?
你明天真的要回波尔卡他家吗
Yes.
对
Where is his house?
他家在哪
Where was it again?
他家在哪来着
Take this.
这个给你
Shinoyama conglomerate,
四乃山财阀
centered around Shinoyama Bank,
以四乃山银行为中心
has total assets of several trillion Yen.
集团总资产都是以兆为单位的
Although not the richest,
虽说四乃山算不上首富
it is also wealthy and influential.
但也是富甲一方了
So, Polka,
而波尔卡你呢
you are the second son of the current head
是四乃山家的现任家主
of the Shinoyama family, Rozan Shinoyama.
也是四乃山吕算的二少爷
Your father, Rozan, is already 79 years old this year.
你的父亲吕算今年已经79岁了
If something unexpected happens to him,
如若吕算发生不测
Polka has the right to inherit his inheritance.
波尔卡将有权利继承吕算的遗产
This could be a reason for someone to target your life.
这足以成为别人盯上你性命的理由
Oh no, my peaceful life.
我安稳的生活啊
Why is Polka himself also surprised?
为什么波尔卡本人也会感到惊讶啊
As I said before,
之前我就说过了
we don't know who commissioned Misaki to kill Polka.
我们并不清楚让美咲 杀掉波尔卡的委托者是谁
But it's very likely that
但对方很有可能
it was someone from your family.
是你的家人
When you go home at this timing,
你挑这种时候回家
it's like rushing into enemy territory.
就和冲进敌营没什么两样
Do you have a way to deal with it?
有办法应付他们吗
Huh? Polka should be able to handle it.
你说什么呀 波尔卡应该能应付过来吧
Only if he can use the magic openly.
如果他能正大光明地使用魔法 自然不成问题
When I was alive, there were guards following me
我活着的时候 身旁有护卫跟着
like double-toothed tiger zombies
像是双牙虎僵尸
and skeleton-heavy armored cavalry.
还有骷髅重甲突骑兵
The things you mentioned are becoming less and less related to peace.
你提到的这些东西 真是越来越跟安稳扯不上边了
I AM A SILENT GUARD, PLEASE DO NOT ASK TOO MUCH. How about this?
(在下乃沉默护卫 莫要多问) 这样如何
If someone rich uses this as a guard,
如果哪家有钱人拿这个充当护卫的话
they will soon become poor.
用不了多久就会变得一贫如洗
Does the guard have to look like a human?
必须得是看起来像人类的护卫吗
Looks like a human…
看起来像人类…
Hey? What are you guys talking about?
咦 你们在说什么呀
What's the deal with Polka?!
波尔卡那家伙到底是怎么回事
He always looks timid,
平日里总是一副怯生生的模样
but suddenly he acts like an elder.
现在他却突然摆出长辈的架子来
Is he really Uncle Polka?
那个人真的是波尔卡叔叔吗
Bro Takeru.
尊哥哥
Why did you go out so late at night?
你们怎么大晚上还跑出去玩呢
Kazuki, Shizuki.
华月 紫月
Very sorry.
我真的十分抱歉
I'm sorry.
对不起
How was it?
怎么样
Is Polka doing well?
波尔卡过得还好吗
Yes.
是的
He said he would go home tomorrow.
他说他明天会回家
I see.
这样啊
That is really something to look forward to.
那还真是令人期待
Having said that, we still need to send a "nanny," just in case.
话虽如此 姑且还是 得安排个“保姆”给你们才行啊
You guys should be careful too.
你们也小心点
After all, no one can say for sure if the same "accident"
毕竟谁都说不准
that happened to Suzuka
还会不会发生
will happen again.
凉火遭遇的那种“事故”
Is that so?
是吗
Polka is safe and sound.
波尔卡他平安无事啊
He started a Shinjuku witchcraft business unexpectedly.
不过他居然在新宿 干起了巫术师的行当
He really resembles you,
和你真是像啊
Kanon.
卡农
It seems like
看样子
I can't die yet.
我还不能死啊
(Episode 6: The Firestarter)
(第6集 The Firestarter -赴火之虫-)